Guide to the Lowrider collection, 1977-1982.
Lowrider collection
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Lowrider collection, 1977-1982.
8098
1 cubic foot.
Printed material.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Many issues of Low Rider Magazine (1977-1982, San Jose, California); two issues of Lowriders are Happening (volume 1, numbers 1 and 2, 1979); one issue of Lowrider Cruisin' (volume 1, number 1, August 1981). Also, Technical low rider, v. 1, no. 1 (1981); Low rider calendar (1980); program for the first national low rider show (1978); press release and publicity photo for the documentary Low 'n slow (1982); issues from Q-vo magazine, v. 1-3 (1979-1981); and Cholo, issue 2 and 3 (1980).
Lowrider culture began in the Chicano (Mexican American) barrios of southern California, and spread from there throughout the United States. It centers around low-slung cars which have been customized and decorated as works of art.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Many issues of Low Rider Magazine (1977-1982, San Jose, California); two issues of Lowriders are Happening (volume 1, numbers 1 and 2, 1979); one issue of Lowrider Cruisin' (volume 1, number 1, August 1981). Also, Technical low rider, v. 1, no. 1 (1981); Low rider calendar (1980); program for the first national low rider show (1978); press release and publicity photo for the documentary Low 'n slow (1982); issues from Q-vo magazine, v. 1-3 (1979-1981); and Cholo, issue 2 and 3 (1980).
SUBJECTS
Subjects:
Mexican Americans -- Social life and customs.; Mexican Americans -- Cultural assimilation.; Lowriders -- United States.; Automobiles -- Social aspects -- United States.; Popular culture -- United States.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
NOTES
The serials Low rider, Q-vo, and Cholo are also cataloged separately.
CONTAINER LIST
- First national low rider show program, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Lowriders are Happening, v. 1 no. 1 & 2, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Low Rider calendar, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Technical Low Rider, v. 1 no. 1, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Low 'n Slow press release, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Low Rider Magazine, v. 1, 1978 (Box 1)
  No. 1-3, 5, 8, 9, 11, 12
- Low Rider Magazine, v. 2, 1978-1979 (Box 2)
  No. 1, 3-6, 9-12
- Low Rider Magazine, v. 3, 1979-1980 (Box 2)
  No. 1-12
- Low Rider Magazine, v. 4, 1980-1981 (Box 3)
- Low Rider Magazine, v. 5, 1981-1982 (Box 3)
  No. 1-5 + June-December issues (issues don't have numbers after #5)
- Cholo Magazine, no. 2 and 3, 1980 (Box 4)
- Q-vo Magazine, v. 1, 1979-1980 (Box 5)
  No. 6, 7, 10, 12
- Q-vo Magazine, v. 2, 1980-1981 (Box 5)
  No. 1, 3, 5, 8-11
- Q-vo Magazine, v. 3, 1981 (Box 5)
  No. 1, 2,